KIM EDWARDS

CONTACT

PORTFOLIO

www.behance.net/kimedwards14c4

EDUCATION

BATHSPA UNIVERSITY

MARCH 2022 — JUNE 2022 Level 6 Web development Bootcamp

GOOGLE

MAY 2021 — March 2022 UX design professional certification

RAVENSBOURNE (LONDON) SEPT

1993 - JUNE 1996

Degree - BA(HONS) Product Design

OXFORD BROOKES UNIVERSITY

SEPT 1992 - JUNE 1993 Foundation Art & Design

CHIPPING NORTON COMPREHENSIVE

SEPT 1985 - JULY 1992

'A' LEVEL - Pure Mathematics • Statistics • Art • Design

GCSE's - Art • Maths • English lit • German English Lang • Science • Further Science • Design and Realisation • Geography

CPD

Introduction to UX and accessible design.

UAL: Creative Computing Institute certificate of achievement. (2021)

Techpixies Social Media Management, CPD certification in Instagram/ Facebook Twitter/linkedin and Pinterest. (2021)

Adobe ACA Certification Web design using Dreamweaver.

City & Guilds HTML for web-design (2000)

Code Academy - HTML & CSS

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

I have taken the opportunity during the pandemic to up-skill, I have completed the Google certification in UX design learning all aspects of UX design from user research through to producing high fidelity prototypes in Figma and Adobe XD.

I have also completed a level 6 web developer Bootcamp with Bath Spa University and the institute of coding, where I have learnt the skills needed to work as a web developer such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.

(VOLUNTEER) CHICKS CHARITY - JUNE 2018 - 2020 Voluntary brand designer

I volunteered as a designer for the Chicks Charity, during this time I created designs for several sub-brands and campaigns for them including the Ice-cream moments campaign, CHICKS memory makers' ball, the signage design & graphics for their new retail shop and the 'Dance the Day away' campaign. Designing effective campaigns which have brought awareness to the CHICKS charity through successful subbrand logos, print and digital collateral that works in harmony within the main CHICKS branding. This role was on a casual voluntary basis

FREELANCE EMPLOYMENT - OCT 2016 - JAN 2018 Self employed freelance designer

Using my extensive experience to manage and coordinate design projects from concept through completion. Liaising closely with clients to create successful design solutions whilst also meeting their deadlines. Using my own imitative to produce original designs for a variety of collateral inc branding, print and digital.

(FREELANCE) EMBLIME - OCT 2016 - OCT 2017 Senior freelance designer

Liaising directly with clients to produce original brand designs, print and digital collateral, wire-framing and website concept designs. I was brought on board to work on the re-branding project for the charity 'Spurgeons' which involved producing branding concepts right through to print and digital ready artwork. Whilst at Emblime I also worked on several projects for B&Q and Mastercard.

GLOBAL HANGER SOLUTIONS LTD. Nov 2012 - Oct 2016 Senior Designer

Whilst working for GHS I designed and produced company branding and assets, print collateral and designed a new company website. I was also responsible for producing artworks to go onto GHS products, for high street brands such as Tommy Hilfiger, Monsoon and Accessorize. My role was very flexible and involved working through the life-cycle of projects from ideation and concept development through to final artworks.

BRAITRIM / BRAIFORM UK - July 1996 - Jan 2010 Senior Product & Graphics Designer

I was employed as a creative graphics and constructional packaging designer, producing innovative new packaging solutions for the garment & gift industry from written or verbal client briefs for high street stores such as Disney store, M&S, Matalan & Mothercare, Debenhams, Crabtree & Evelyn to name a few.

I was responsible for all stages of the design process from concepts, producing cutterguides, through to creating print ready artwork. The packaging solutions being mainly produced from card, polypropylene etc. I gained a full appreciation of 2d and 3d packaging & graphics techniques, and also the importance of studying current & future Market trends. I gained a strong understanding of the industry and clients needs, being able to provide realistic working packaging solutions.

KIM EDWARDS

CONTACT

PORTFOLIO

www.behance.net/kimedwards14c4

SKILLS

- Adobe Creative Suite
- · Adobe Illustrator
- InDesign
- Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Product Design
- Graphic Design
- Packaging design
- UX Design
- UI Design
- Wire-framing and prototyping
- User journey Mapping and storyboarding
- Constructional cutter-guides
- CAD
- Print Design including tickets, labels, flyers, posters, promotional goods, brochures.etc.
- Branding and Sub-branding.
- Logo Design
- Web / App design
- Digital Design
- HTML & CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT
- Design systems

PERSONAL STATEMENT

During the pandemic I have up-skilled and have completed the Google UX Design professional certificate, being one of the first people in the UK to achieve this. I have also recently undertaken a 12 week intensive level 6 web developer bootcamp with Bath Spa University / Institute of coding.

I am currently seeking employment within a junior role where I can use my newly acquired skills along side my existing design skills

I am an experienced designer with a product design degree and proven working experience in many areas of the design industry. My design experience spans many years of employment in the design industry, I have worked for a wide variety of brands such as Disney Store UK, Matalan, Debenhams, Crabtree and Evelyn and have experience on a wide variety of projects from initial research through to mood / style boards, concepts and producing die-lines and also print ready and digital artworks. UX and UI for mobile and desktop.

I am self-motivated and approach my work with a methodical manner. This enables me to produce creative yet viable solutions for the real world. I am very interested in how users interact with products / designs and always approach any problem from a UX perspective.

I am conversant in the Adobe Suite in particular Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign and Photoshop.

I have also completed an Adobe Education course on Adobe XD and have achieved my Adobe ACA certification in web design using Dreamweaver. I more recently have learnt to use Figma for wireframing and prototyping

I have a drive to learn more and am continually trying to improve upon my skills, having shown this by attending several courses outside of my employment to further my skills in other areas of design such as: City & Guilds in HTML, Adobe Flash, Adobe ACA certification in Adobe Dreamweaver, Google UX certification & more recently by attending an intensive 12 week Web Developer Bootcamp

I have a very hands on approach to work, and flourish in an environment where I can learn from experience gained in role. I am able to work well with individuals at all management levels and to adapt a working style appropriate to the environment/audience.

I have attention to detail and am able to plan well in advance to deadlines. I enjoy completing projects and tasks efficiently to a high quality.

I enjoy visualising processes and conceptualising and solving problems, and I continuously seek an understanding of how things function and work and I enjoy roles which require continuous learning and applying new skills and ways of thinking.